And now! At Last! Another film completely different from some of the
other films which aren't quite the same as this one is.
Monty Python and the Holy Grail is a adventure, comedy,
fantasy film directed by Terry Jones.
King Arthur, accompanied by his squire, recruits his Knights of the Round Table, including Sir Bedevere the Wise,
Sir Lancelot the Brave, Sir Robin the Not-Quite-So-Brave-As-Sir-Lancelot and Sir Galahad the Pure.
On the way, Arthur battles the Black Knight who, despite having had
all his limbs chopped off, insists he can still fight.
They reach Camelot, but Arthur decides not  to enter, as "it is a silly place".
King Arthur / Voice of God / Middle Head /
Hiccoughing Guard, played by Graham Chapman.
Second Swallow-Savvy Guard / The Black Knight / Peasant 3 / Sir Launcelot the Brave
/ Taunting French Guard / Tim the Enchanter, played by John Cleese.
Dead Collector / Peasant 1 / Sir Robin the Not-Quite-So-Brave-as-Sir Launcelot / First Swamp
Castle Guard / Concorde / Roger the Shrubber / Brother Maynard, played by Eric Idle.
Patsy / Green Knight / Old Man from Scene 24 (Bridgekeeper) / Sir Bors
/ Animator / Gorilla Hand, played by Terry Gilliam.
Dennis's Mother / Sir Bedevere / Left Head / Prince Herbert /
Voice of Cartoon Scribe, played by Terry Jones.
First Swallow-Savvy Guard / Dennis / Peasant 2 / Right Head / Sir Galahad the Pure / Narrator / King of Swamp
Castle / Brother Maynard's Brother / Leader of The Knights Who Say NI!, played by Michael Palin.
Monty Python and the Holy Grail is a 1975 British comedy film  based on the Arthurian legend, written and performed by the Monty Python comedy group (Graham
Chapman, John Cleese, Terry Gilliam, Eric Idle, Terry Jones, and Michael Palin) and directed by Gilliam and Jones in their feature directorial debuts.
It was conceived during the hiatus between the third and fourth series of
their BBC Television series Monty Python's Flying Circus.
While the group's first film, And Now for Something Completely Different, was a compilation of sketches from the first two
television series, Holy Grail is an original story that parodies the legend of King Arthur's quest for the Holy Grail.
Thirty years later, Idle used the film as the basis for the
2005 Tony Award-winning musical Spamalot.
Monty Python and the Holy Grail grossed more than any other British film screened in the US in
1975, and has since been considered one of the greatest comedy films of all time.
In the US, it was selected in 2011 as the second-best comedy of all time in the ABC
special Best in Film: The Greatest Movies of Our Time behind Airplane!.
In the UK, readers of Total Film magazine in 2000 ranked it the fifth-greatest comedy film
of all time; a similar poll of Channel 4 viewers in 2006 placed it sixth.
The film explores themes of holy grail, swordplay,
england, monk, wedding reception.
The tone is lighthearted.